Hello YouTubers, here is the guy with the
Swiss accent.
Currently, I have viewers from 147 countries.
This is great!
But many additional people would like to watch
my videos but do not understand enough English
to follow the rather complex stuff.
And from time to time, I even had requests
for making my videos in another language,
or at least, add subtitles in other languages.
So, I decided to start this experiment: But,
to achieve this, I need your help!
I am searching for a programmer to program
a small tool, and a few guys who want to support
me by creating subtitles in their native languages.
YouTube has a functionality where the community
can translate the description of videos and
create subtitles.
This is a great feature.
But, of course, it is a lot of work to add
such comments or subtitles.
If you go into the “more” tab below a
video, you find “translations”.
There, you can add either title and description,
or subtitles in your language.
Just chose the language and then, upload your
file with the translated text and the respective
times when the subtitles have to appear.
Then, you can watch the video and adjust the
times if necessary.
At the end, you can submit it, either to the
community, or to me for approval.
This is not too complicated.
But, where does the file for the uploading
come from?
To support you as much as possible, I have
the following proposal: As you know, I use
a script for most of my videos.
The only exceptions are Mailbags and semi-live
videos.
If you are willing to help, I will send you
the respective script file and you can translate
it to your language.
Maybe it is even worthwhile to start with
Google translate.
I know, this is a big work, and this cannot
be done by me, because I do not speak your
language.
But it adds a lot of value for other people
in your country, or even around the world.
To support this process, I wrote an Excel
macro which reads your translated text file,
divides it into small junks, inserts all the
needed times, and creates a subtitles file
which can be uploaded YouTube.
Of course, the times are not always completely
right, because I just divide the length of
the whole video by the number of subtitles.
But I tested it, and it was not too bad for
a start.
And you still have the chance to adjust it
as shown before.
We all know, that Excel macros are not ideal
to format text.
So, I search also a programmer which uses
the ideas in the Excel macro and writes a
decent program.
It should be able to ask for the number of
letters per subtitle, the file name of the
source and destination file, the length of
the video and then, read your translated file
and outputs an SBV file which can be uploaded
to YouTube.
The program should be easy to use.
I do not care about the language it is written
in.
And what do you get for all this work?
Of course, I cannot pay you.
But I thought, I would create a page for each
one of you on my blog with a picture, a text,
and the episodes you translated.
Of course, only, if you want to disclose your
identity.
And maybe, it is a way to give a something
back to the community.
BTW, this was my primary reason to start this
channel…
If you are interested to try it out, please
drop me a message here on YouTube, on Twitter,
or Facebook.
And tell me, with which episode you would
like to start and in which language you would
like to translate.
Here is the list of the most successful episodes.
Maybe it would be a good idea if we start
with these.
I hope, I will get a response from a few of
you and we can start our experiment.
Thank you very much!